Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1907-1971; Series I; 79.8; 183 boxes
  - A-Z Correspondence
    - Wendell, Evert Jansen, 1916 May 16 (Box 170, Folder 2165)
    - Werner, Nat, 1945–1946 (Box 170, Folder 2166)
    - Wescott, Barbara, 1956–1959 (Box 170, Folder 2167)
    - Wescott, Glenway, 1924-1964, undated (Box 170, Folder 2168)
    - West, Mary A., 1921 March 3 (Box 170, Folder 2169)
    - West, Rebecca, 1925 May 11 (Box 170, Folder 2170)
    - White Barn Theatre, 1955–1959 (Box 170, Folder 2171)
    - Whitney, Gertrude Vanderbilt, 1939 May 24 (Box 170, Folder 2172)
    - Whitney, Helen Hay, 1931 December 8 (Box 170, Folder 2173)
    - Who's Who Publications, Inc., 1928; undated (Box 171, Folder 2174)
    - Wiener, Paul Lester, 1939; 1964 (Box 171, Folder 2175)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1949 April 8 (Box 171, Folder 2176)
    - Willa, Susan, undated (Box 171, Folder 2177)
    - William R. Scott, Inc., 1939–1942 (Box 171, Folder 2178)
    - Williams, Almenia, 1948–1964 (Box 171, Folder 2179-2180)
      Includes photograph of Williams' two sons, and photograph of Williams with fiancé, enclosed with letters from Williams to CVV and FM (1957)
    - Williams, Walter, 1950 (Box 171, Folder 2181)
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1916 (Box 171, Folder 2182)
    - Wilson, Gilbert Brown, 1948-1954, undated (Box 171, Folder 2183-2184)
      Includes correspondence, typescript synopsis, and other material regarding Wilson's opera libretto, "The White Whale"
    - Wilson, Robert A. (Robert Alfred), 1960; 1964 (Box 171, Folder 2185)
    - Windham, Donald
      - 1949–1960 (Box 171, Folder 2186-2189)
        Includes photograph of Sandy Campbell, with note from Windham to CVV on verso (1955); photographic postcards of Windham and Campbell, with notes from Windham to CVV on versos (1960); photograph of Windham, enclosed with letter from Windham to CVV (1960); letter from Edward White, Charles Scribner's Sons, to CVV (1962)
      - Galley proofs, 1962–1963 (Box 181 (Oversize), Folder 2327)
        Galley proofs of "Gentian," by Windham, with note from Windhamto CVV on first page (1962); galley proofs of "Myopia," by Windham, with note from Windham to CVV on first page (1963)
    - Winslow, Kathryn, 1950–1952 (Box 171, Folder 2190)
      Includes photograph of cats, enclosed with letter from Winslow to CVV (1950)
    - Winston Churchill Memorial and Library in the United States, 1964 (Box 171, Folder 2191)
    - Wittgenstein, Victor, 1931–1960 (Box 171, Folder 2192)
    - Wolfe, Thomas, 1939–1960 (Box 171, Folder 2193)
      Consists of letters from Wolfe family members and people requesting CVV's photographs of Wolfe
    - Wolff, Kurt, 1941 August (Box 171, Folder 2194)
      Includes letter from Wolff, with letter of introduction to Wolff from Yolande Gregory to CVV
    - Wolff, Miriam, 1958–1964 (Box 171, Folder 2195)
      Includes note from Jack (Jacob) Marinoff to FM, enclosed with letter from Wolff to FM (1961)
    - Wolfington, Iggie, 1971 June 10 (Box 171, Folder 2196)
    - Wong, Anna May, 1929–1961 (Box 172, Folder 2197-2204)
      Includes notes signed by Wong's brother Richard (Kim) Wong; two photographs of Wong's cat, enclosed with letter from Wong to CVV and FM (1957)
    - Wong, Richard, 1940–1964 (Box 172, Folder 2205-2206)
      Includes photograph of Wong, his wife, Carol Wong, and daughter Dawn Wong, enclosed in greeting card to CVV and FM (1964)
    - Wood, Peggy, 1931–1964 (Box 172, Folder 2207)
    - Woods, A. G., 1932 January 29 (Box 172, Folder 2208)
    - Woods, Alice, 1913; undated (Box 172, Folder 2209)
    - Woollcott, Alexander, 1938-1940, undated (Box 172, Folder 2210)
    - Woollett, Walter, 1932 (Box 172, Folder 2211)
    - Workmen's Circle (U.S.). Home for the Aged of New York State (Bronx, New York, N.Y.), 1957–1964 (Box 172, Folder 2212)
    - Worth, Irene, 1960; 1964 (Box 172, Folder 2213)
    - Worthington, Marjorie Muir, 1932–1954 (Box 172, Folder 2214-2215)
      Includes two photographic postcards of Worthington's home in Rhinebeck, New York, with notes to CVV and FM on versos (1938)
      See also: William Seabrook
    - Wright, Cuthbert, 1915 May 7 (Box 172, Folder 2216)
    - Wylie, Elinor, 1923–1937 (Box 172, Folder 2217)
      Includes third-party letters regarding Wylie's correspondence with CVV, and the Elinor Wylie Poetry Fellowship (1937)
      See also: Photoduplicated letters from Wylie to CVV in Box 176
    - "Y" General, 1920–1963 (Box 173, Folder 2218)
    - Yale, Helen, 1959; 1964 (Box 173, Folder 2219)
      Includes photograph of Yale's sons Nicky and Steven Yale, enclosed with letter from Yale to FM (1959)
    - Yale Poetry Review, 1947 (Box 173, Folder 2220)
    - Yale Review, 1921 February 7 (Box 173, Folder 2221)
    - Yale University
      - Alumni Board, 1961–1964 (Box 173, Folder 2222)
      - Art Gallery, 1951 (Box 173, Folder 2223)
      - Division of the Fine Arts. Department of the History of Art, 1949 December 1 (Box 173, Folder 2224)
      - Library
        - Correspondence, 1942–1969 (Box 173, Folder 2225-2228)
        - Gift acknowledgements, 1940-1964, undated (Box 173, Folder 2229-2234)
        - Gift lists
          - General Library, circa 1946-1955 (Box 174, Folder 2235)
          - Anna Marble Pollock Memorial Library of Books about Cats, circa 1947-1964 (Box 174, Folder 2236)
          - Collection of American Literature, 1946–1964 (Box 174, Folder 2237-2238)
          - Gertrude Stein Collection, undated (Box 174, Folder 2239)
          - James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts and Letters, circa 1941-1964 (Box 174, Folder 2240-2242)
            Includes draft of letter from CVV to Donald Gallup dated 1962 October 23, and typescript list, carbon copy, of Kodachrome photographs
      - Office of the President, 1955–1964 (Box 174, Folder 2243)
      - Office of the Secretary, 1931–1964 (Box 174, Folder 2244)
        Includes letter from Secretary Carl Albert Lohmann to Robert B. Stearns (1931)
      - School of the Fine Arts. Department of Drama, 1949–1950 (Box 174, Folder 2245)
      - Yale University Press, 1947–1964 (Box 174, Folder 2246)
        Includes memorandum of agreement between Yale University Press and CVV regarding the publication of Four in America by Gertrude Stein (1947)
    - Yalman, June, 1956–1957 (Box 175, Folder 2247)
    - Yiddish Art Theatre, 1933 (Box 175, Folder 2248)
    - Yoder, Theodore
      - 1951–1953 (Box 175, Folder 2249)
      - Newspaper clipping, 1950 January 27 (Box 182 (Oversize), Folder 2340)
        Clipping from the Orlando Morning Sentinel
    - Yuka, Blanche, 1964 December 22 (Box 175, Folder 2250)
    - "Z" General, 1926-1964 (Box 175, Folder 2251)
    - Ziffren, Lester, 1935–1936 (Box 175, Folder 2252)
    - Zigrosser, Carl, 1931–1951 (Box 175, Folder 2253)
    - Zimbalist, Efrem, 1933; 1946 (Box 175, Folder 2254)
    - Zlotchever, Eve, 1918 February 21 (Box 175, Folder 2255)
    - Unidentified, 1909-1964, undated (Box 175, Folder 2256-2257)
  - Copies of Correspondence From Other Manuscript Repositories
    - Blixen, Karen, 1954-1962, undated (Box 176, Folder 2258)
      Letters from CVV to Blixen
      Acquired from Kongelige Bibliotek
    - Cabell, James Branch, 1919–1932 (Box 176, Folder 2259)
      Letters to CVV
      Acquired from the New York Public Library
    - Dreiser, Theodore, 1923–1938 (Box 176, Folder 2260)
      Letters from CVV to Dreiser
      Acquired from The University of Pennsylvania Rare Book Collection
    - Ficke, Arthur Davidson, 1920–1928 (Box 176, Folder 2261)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1925–1926 (Box 176, Folder 2262)
    - Hergesheimer, Joseph, 1920–1932 (Box 176, Folder 2263)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1922-1923, undated (Box 176, Folder 2264)
    - Mencken, H.L. (Henry Louis), 1916–1924 (Box 176, Folder 2265)
    - Stagg, Hunter T. (Hunter Taylor), 1923-1934, undated (Box 176, Folder 2266-2267)
      Letters from CVV to Stagg
      Acquired from Stagg's niece, Charlotte Nance Saylor, 1978, and Edgar MacDonald, 1981
    - Stein, Gertrude, 1917–1932 (Box 176, Folder 2268)
    - Wylie, Elinor, 1925–1926 (Box 176, Folder 2269)
      Letter to CVV
  - Greeting Cards
    - Holiday cards, 1963 (Box 177, Folder 2270-2280)
    - Cat-themed cards
      Include postcards and greeting cards with depictions of cats
      - 1917-1966, undated (Box 178, Folder 2281-2288)
      - 1946, undated (Box 181 (Oversize), Folder 2328)
- Writings, 1913-1966; Series II; 6.3; 9 boxes + 1 broadside
  Organized in seven subseries: Books; Articles and Essays; Reviews; Addresses and Speeches; Miscellaneous Writings; Notes; and Writings by Others. Van Vechten's writings are arranged alphabetically within each subseries. Writings by Others are arranged by name of author.
  Series II, Writings, includes material documenting Van Vechten's books, articles and essays, reviews, addresses and speeches, miscellaneous writings, and notes. In addition to manuscripts, typescripts, and proofs of his writings, notes, correspondence, and clippings related to specific writings are included. The subseries Writings by Others includes works written for Van Vechten, or in his honor; two Master's theses written about Van Vechten; Coleman Dowell's stage adaptation of Van Vechten's The Tattooed Countess; and poems and limericks collected by Van Vechten. In addition to libretti by Henry Butler for an operatic adaptation of Eugene O'Neill's Mourning Becomes Electra, vocal scores for several works by Marvin David Levy are included in the subseries. Typescript copies of Gertrude Stein's stage play Yes Is For a Very Young Man are also included.
  - Books
    - Blind Bow-Boy
      - Reviews, 1923 (Box 183, Folder 2341)
        Clippings
    - Excavations: A Book of Advocacies
      - "On Visiting Fashionable Places Out of Season", undated (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2524)
        Galley proofs of pages numbered 1-282, signed by CVV
      - Reviews, 1926 (Box 183, Folder 2342)
    - Firecrackers
      - Reviews, 1925–1927 (Box 183, Folder 2343)
    - In a Garret
      - "In the Theatres of the Purlieus", [1920] (Box 183, Folder 2344)
        Pages 287-347
      - Reviews, 1920 (Box 183, Folder 2345)
    - Interpreters and Interpretations
      - Reviews, 1917, 1920 (Box 183, Folder 2346)
    - The Merry Go Round
      - "Impressions in the Theatre", 1918 (Box 183, Folder 2347)
        Pages [179]-330 of publication
      - "The Land of Joy", 1918 (Box 183, Folder 2348)
        Proofs of pages numbered 89-101, with manuscript corrections in unidentified hand
    - Music and Bad Manners
      - Reviews, 1916–1917 (Box 183, Folder 2349)
    - Parties: Scenes from Contemporary New York Life
      - Galley proofs of pages numbered 1-260, xii-xiv, signed by CVV, and stamped "The Plimpton Press, June 4 1930" (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2525-2527)
      - Advertisements, undated (Box 183, Folder 2350)
        Clipping and postcard
    - Peter Whiffle
      - Reviews, 1922, 1929 (Box 183, Folder 2351)
    - Red
      - Review, 1925 (Box 183, Folder 2352)
        Clipping
    - Sacred and Profane Memories
      - Galley proofs of title page, dedication, foreward, table of contents, and quote from Verlaine, with autograph corrections; stamped "The Plimpton Press, Dec 10 1931", 1931 December 10 (Box 183, Folder 2352a)
      - Galley proofs of pages numbered 1-230, xvii-xx, signed by CVV, with proofreader's marks, and stamped "The Plimpton Press, Feb 10 1932", 1932 February 10 (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2528-2530)
      - Galley proofs of pages numbered xvii-xx, unmarked, undated (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2531)
      - Proof sheet of photographs with captions, unmarked, undated (Box 191 (Broadside))
      - Reviews, 1932 (Box 183, Folder 2353)
    - Spider Boy: a Scenario for a Moving Picture
      - Galley proofs of pages numbered 1-297, signed by CVV, and stamped "The Plimpton Press, Apr 25 1928", 1928 April 25 (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2532-2534)
      - Reviews, 1928 (Box 183, Folder 2354)
    - The Tattooed Countess
      - Reviews, 1924–1961 (Box 183, Folder 2355)
        Clippings including reviews of the book, film, and stage musical, and articles regarding the musical adaptation
    - The Tiger in the House
      - Advertisement flyers, undated (Box 183, Folder 2356)
      - Reviews, 1921, 1926 (Box 183, Folder 2357)
    - Excerpts from book reviews, circa 1922-1928 (Box 183, Folder 2358)
      Typescript book review excerpts, possibly to be used for blurbs; with publicity brochure
    - Excerpts from letters to CVV regarding his books, 1924–1955 (Box 183, Folder 2359)
      Typescripts
    - Suggestions and corrections for Carl Van Vechten books, 1924–1931 (Box 183, Folder 2360)
      Letters to CVV from readers suggesting editorial changes and corrections to books including The Tattooed Countess, Excavations, Nigger Heaven, Spider Boy, and Parties; correspondence with Knopf regarding corrections; autograph notes by CVV regarding corrections
  - Articles and Essays
    - [Abraham Walkowitz], 1949 May 1 (Box 184, Folder 2361)
      Typescript, corrected
    - "Alfred A. Knopf and the Borzoi Press", 1922 March 7 (Box 184, Folder 2362)
    - ["Alfred Stieglitz"], 1947 February (Box 184, Folder 2363)
      Drafts, typescript, with corrections; accompanied by typed letter, carbon, from CVV to Mrs. [Dorothy] Norman regarding a Steigliz memorial volume which she edited
    - "Anna Pavlova", 1920 October 7 (Box 184, Folder 2364)
      Extract from "Pastiches et Pistaches" in The Reviewer, January 1924
      Three drafts, typescript, with corrections
    - "Another Point of View on The Land of Joy ", 1917 November 9 (Box 184, Folder 2365)
      Clipping of published letter to the theater columnist of The New York Evening Globe
    - "La Belle Epoche", 1963 July 25 (Box 184, Folder 2366)
      Drafts, autograph and typescript
    - "A Birthday Carnation for George [Gershwin]", 1958 January (Box 184, Folder 2367)
      Draft, typescript, with corrections, signed by CVV; draft, typescript fragment, signed by CVV
    - "A Camellia for Marguerite", 1954 (Box 184, Folder 2368)
      Page proofs, with autograph corrections
    - "Carl Van Vechten", 1949 (Box 184, Folder 2369)
      Drafts, typescript with autograph corrections; typed mimeograph letter, dated 1949 March, from Leo Perper, president of Roger Kent, announcing an exhibit of CVV documentary photographs of celebrated personalities, with typescript mimeograph of CVV biography
    - "Channing Pollock's Politely Bawdy Christmas Verses", 1947 November (Box 184, Folder 2370)
      Drafts, with autograph corrections, signed by CVV; autograph notes
    - "The Coming New York Season", 1909 December (Box 184, Folder 2371)
      Issue of The New Music Review
    - "Comments on Improvisations of New York: A Symphony in Lines by A. Walkowitz"
      - Drafts, typescript original and carbon, with autograph corrections, 1947 (Box 184, Folder 2372)
      - Improvisations of New York: A Symphony in Lines by A. Walkowitz (Girard, Kansas: Haldeman-Julius Publications, 1948) (Box 184, Folder 2373)
    - [Comments on Anton Dolin and Alicia Markova], undated (Box 184, Folder 2374)
      Drafts, typescript, with autograph corrections
    - "Cosas de España", undated (Box 184, Folder 2375)
      Draft, typescript, with autograph corrections
    - "An Epilogue", 1946 (Box 184, Folder 2375a)
      Clippings of CVV's obituary for Gertrude Stein, published as "Pigeons and Roses Pass, Alas; Van Vechten Writes a Brilliant Memorial to Miss Gertrude Stein," in the New York Post, 1946 December 9, and in an unidentified and undated newspaper as "An Epilogue: Gertrude Stein's 'Now Puzzling God'"
    - "Erik Satie: Master of the Rigolo", 1918 March (Box 184, Folder 2376)
      Clipping, Vanity Fair
    - [Essays on Martha Graham], 1963 (Box 184, Folder 2377)
      Drafts, typescript with autograph corrections, of "The Contribution of Martha Graham" (1963 November 14), and two untitled essays (1963 October 24, undated); with advertisement for "An Evening With Martha Graham" at Lincoln Center (undated), and clipping of article from The London Observer of "Graham the Great" by Alexander Bland (1963 September 1)
    - "Fabulous Hollywood", 1927 March (Box 184, Folder 2378)
      Draft, typescript carbon,with autograph corrections; with clipping from Vanity Fair (1927 May)
    - [Fania Marinoff], 1960 August 25 (Box 184, Folder 2379)
      Drafts, typescript with autograph corrections
    - "A Few Notes about Four Saints in Three Acts ", 1934 February 8 (Box 184, Folder 2380)
      Introduction to Four Saints in Three Acts: An Opera to be Sung by Gertrude Stein (New York: Random House, 1934)
      Drafts, typescript original and carbon, with autograph corrections, and inscription to Yale University Library dated 1941 May 21
    - "A Few Memories of Florine [Stettheimer]", 1962 April 14 (Box 184, Folder 2381)
    - "A Few Notes A Propos of a 'Little' Novel of Thank You", 1958 (Box 184, Folder 2382)
      Foreward to A Novel of Thank You, by Gertrude Stein (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1958)
      Drafts, typescript original and carbon, with autograph corrections; with CVV's typescript editorial notes regarding volume
    - "A Few Words Relating to My Photographs", 1961 August 19 (Box 184, Folder 2383)
      Draft, typescript carbon, with autograph corrections
    - "The Fifth Alternative", 1915 December (Box 184, Folder 2384)
      Clipping, Snappy Stories
    - [Florine Stettheimer], undated (Box 184, Folder 2385)
      Draft, typescript, with autograph corrections, signed by CVV
    - "Forsan et haec Olim meminesse iuvabit", 1964 (Box 184, Folder 2386)
      Drafts, typescript, with autograph corrections, regarding Goddard Lieberson
    - "Foreward" to the Catalogue of the Alfred Stieglitz Collection for Fisk University, 1949 May 19 (Box 184, Folder 2387)
      Draft, typescript, with autograph corrections; with copy of the Catalogue (1949)
    - "George Gershwin", 1925 January 4 (Box 184, Folder 2388)
      Published in Vanity Fair, 1925 March, as "George Gershwin: An American Composer Who is Writing Notable Music in the Jazz Idiom"
      Draft, typescript carbon, with autograph corrections; with "My Diary," typescript list of meetings with Gershwin
    - "George Gershwin", 1958 February 5 (Box 184, Folder 2389)
      Draft, typescript carbon, with autograph corrections; with typescript biographical notes on Gershwin
    - "The Gertrude Stein Story", 1950 (Box 184, Folder 2390)
      Recorded for broadcast on WNYC, February 1, 1950
    - "A Good Little Devil" [Fritzi Scheff]
      - Draft, typescript carbon, with autograph corrections, signed by CVV, 1954 April 21 (Box 184, Folder 2391)
      - Issue of Saturday Review, 1954 May 29 (Box 184, Folder 2392)
    - [Henry Fuller], 1929 October 30 (Box 184, Folder 2393)
    - "Hollywood Parties"
      - Draft, typescript carbon, with autograph corrections, 1927 March 10 (Box 184, Folder 2394)
      - Clipping, Vanity Fair, 1927 June (Box 184, Folder 2395)
    - "Hollywood Royalty", 1927 July (Box 184, Folder 2396)
    - "How I Listen to Four Saints in Three Acts "
      - Drafts, typescript, with autograph corrections, 1934 February (Box 184, Folder 2397)
      - Souvenir production program for Four Saints in Three Acts, inscribed by CVV to Yale University Library, November 22, 1940, 1934 (Box 184, Folder 2398)
    - "How I Remember Joseph Hergesheimer"
      - Drafts, typescript, with autograph corrections, 1947 October (Box 184, Folder 2399)
      - Page proofs, unmarked, [undated] (Box 184, Folder 2400)
      - Galley proofs, unmarked, [undated] (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2535)
    - "How Many Acts Are There in It?", 1948 (Box 184, Folder 2401)
      Introduction to Last Operas and Plays by Gertrude Stein, edited by Carl Van Vechten (New York: Rinehart & Co., 1949)
    - "How to Read Gertrude Stein", 1914 August (Box 184, Folder 2402)
      Clipping, The Trend, signed and annotated by CVV
    - "Introducing Mr. Knopf, or Alfred in a Nutshell", 1952 February 27 (Box 184, Folder 2403)
      Drafts, typescript, with autograph corrections, signed by CVV
    - [Introduction to the Yale Edition of the Unpublished Writings of Gertrude Stein (1951)] (Box 184, Folder 2404)
      Drafts, typescript original and carbon, with autograph corrections
    - "An Introduction with Candor and Some Little Truth", 1960 January 18 (Box 184, Folder 2405)
      Introduction to Between Friends: Letters of James Branch Cabell and Others (New York: Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc., 1962)
    - "MA-Draper", 1962 October 27 (Box 185, Folder 2406)
    - "Marguerite D'Alvarez: A Remarkable Tribute to a Remarkable Artist", 1920 April 22 (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2536)
      Two copies of advertisement with CVV's tribute to D'Alvarez, reprinted from the April 22, 1920 issue of the Musical Courier, inscribed "for Max from Carlo," and "To My dearest Marinoff with all my love, Carlo"
    - "Mary Garden's Transcendent Art", 1918 February 6 (Box 185, Folder 2407)
      Clipping of letter from CVV to Pitts Sanborn, music columnist for The New York Evening Globe
    - "Massenet and Women", 1913 February (Box 185, Folder 2408)
    - "Mina Loy: A New Poet", undated (Box 185, Folder 2409)
    - "More Laurels for Our Gertrude", 1964 (Box 185, Folder 2410)
      Gotham Book Mart catalog of Gertrude Stein books, manuscripts, etc.
    - "Mr. Cabell of Lichfield and Poictesme"
      - Draft, typescript, with autograph corrections, 1948 April 6 (Box 185, Folder 2411)
      - Galley proofs, with autograph corrections, 1948 (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2537)
      - Issue of the Yale University Library Gazette, 1948 July (Box 185, Folder 2412)
    - "Mr. Strawinsky's Pedigree", [1916] Febraruary 24 (Box 185, Folder 2413)
      Clipping of letter from CVV to the editor of New York Globe and Commerce
    - "A Note on a Young Composer [Richard Hundley]", 1964 March (Box 185, Folder 2414)
    - "Notes for an Autobiography", 1930 (Box 185, Folder 2415)
      "Compiled for The Colophon in June, 1930"
      Printed, four-page essay
    - "Notes Written on Stone", 1951 (Box 185, Folder 2416)
      Essay appearing in the program for the Living Theatre's production of Doctor Faustus Lights the Lights, Cherry Lane Theatre, New York, 1951
      Draft, typescript, with autograph corrections, signed by CVV; with copy of the Living Theatre production program, 1951
    - "An Ode to the Stage Door Canteen", 1943 February 14 (Box 185, Folder 2417)
    - "On the Relative Difficulties of Depicting Heaven and Hell in Music", 1919 October (Box 185, Folder 2418)
      Issue of The Musical Quarterly
    - "The Origin of the Sonnets from the Patagonian"
      - Drafts, typescript originals and carbons, with autograph corrections, 1914–1958 (Box 185, Folder 2419)
      - Issue of Hartwick Review, 1967 (Box 185, Folder 2420)
    - "Overture to a List of Books"
      Foreward to A First List of Books Printed and Published by The Banyan Press, 1948
      - Drafts, typescript originals and carbons, with autograph corrections, 1948 May 2 (Box 185, Folder 2421)
      - A First List of Books Printed and Published by The Banyan Press, [1948] (Box 185, Folder 2422)
    - "Pastiches et Pistaches", 1922–1924 (Box 185, Folder 2423-2428)
      Sketches published in The Reviewer, 1922-1924
      Drafts, typescript originals and carbons, with autograph corrections; clippings, The Reviewer
    - [Pierre Monteux], undated (Box 185, Folder 2429)
    - "Pour Amuser Rich", 1917 August (Box 185, Folder 2430)
      Clipping, with corrections, Ronwrong, August 1917
    - "Puss in Books"
      - Drafts, typescript, with autograph corrections, 1949 (Box 185, Folder 2431)
      - Galley proofs, 1949 (Box 190 (Oversize), Folder 2538)
    - "Random Notes on Mr. Mencken of Baltimore"